(独家: 面对银行犯罪团伙 警方毫无头绪)
(十八个月前)
他们竟然就这样被无罪释放了!
They just walked out of there!
对 我知道 当时我就坐在你旁边
Yeah, I know, I was sort of sitting next to you.
沃特斯兄弟 他们竟然就这样被无罪释放了!
The whole Waters family. They just walked right out of there!
- 再说一次 我当时也在场  - 他们究竟怎么做到的?!
- Again, I was in the room.  - How do they always manage that?!
他们很聪明
They're good.
他们很贪婪 还会再次作案的
They're greedy and they'll do it again,
下一次 我们要把他们抓个现行
and next time we're going to catch them in the act.
怎么抓?
How?
(谁偷了我们的两百万?)
(十二个月前)
还是没抓到?
No good?
他们总是知道我们要来了 他们到底是怎么知道的?!
They always know we're coming. How do they always know?!
他们很聪明 也很擅长
They're good, they work at it.
- 他们永远不会停下  - 我们也不会
- They're never going to stop.  - Well, neither are we.
(离沃特斯兄弟定罪尚远  警方仍无进展)
(六个月前)
(沃特斯兄弟如入无人之境 再次逍遥法外)
(三个月前)
格雷格...
Greg...
抓现行!
In the act!
这是我们唯一的方法 抓现行!
It's the only way we're going to do this, in the act!
(昨天)
(所有警报解除)
(警报离线)
(发现黑客袭击)
他们还屏蔽着警报装置?
They're still blocking it?
没错 很有效的黑客技术
Yeah. Very efficiently hacked.
他们一定满意得要死
They must be bloody pleased with themselves.
肯定的
They must be.
现在行动?
Right then?
不! 不 您来负责这次逮捕行动 这是您的功劳 头儿
Ah, no! No, you've got to make the arrest. This one's yours, boss.
你以前从没叫过我"头儿"
You've never called me boss before.
好吧 今天我心情非常好 所以才叫
Oh, well, look what happens when you're good.
你也知道没几天好心情的日子吧?
You know how most days aren't good days?
- 今天是个好日子  - 不过对沃特斯团伙来说可不是
- This is a good day.  - Not for the Waters family.
好了 屋顶安排了十个人 所有出口都有人把手
OK, ten men on the roof, all exits covered.
银行关门了 因此我们不用担心有人质
The bank's closed, so we've no hostages to worry about.
不好意思 继续 继续
Sorry, no, go on. Go on.
嗯 我们在隧道入口处也安排了人手...
Um, we've got the tunnel entrance covered...
大卫斯 魏楼 克里斯蒂
and Davies, Willow and Christie
正在马弗京路上指挥武装部队响应
are heading up armed response on Mafeking Road.
- 不好意思 我还是得看一下手机  - 是他 对吧?
- Sorry, I'd better get this.  - It's him, isn't it?
(救命 贝克街 现在)
(救救我 拜托了)
- 我... 我得走了  - 什么?!
- I, I, I have to go.  - What?!
- 你来逮捕他们  - 不可能!
- You make the arrest.  - No way!
对不起 你能做到 不用管我
Sorry, you'll be fine. I'm cool with this.
如果你现在走了 琼斯就会抢了所有功劳 你知道他就是这种人
Jones will get all the credit if you leave now, you know he will.
好吧 没关系了 我得走了
Yeah, well, yeah, it doesn't matter, I have to go.
请求支援! 我需要最大警力支援!
Back up! I need maximum back up!
贝克街 马上!
Baker Street now!
出了什么事?!
What's going on?!
- 这很难  - 什么?
- This is hard.  - What?
真的很难 这是我做过最难的事了
Really hard. Hardest thing I've ever had to do.
你知道什么约翰的趣事吗?
Do you know any funny stories about John?
什么?!
What?!
我需要趣闻轶事 你没惹麻烦吧?
I need anecdotes. Didn't go to any trouble, did you?
《神探夏洛克》
《三签名》
- 闭嘴 哈德森太太  - 我一个字都没说
- Shut up, Mrs Hudson.  - I haven't said a word.
你在组织语言问一个问题
You're formulating a question,
看你思考的过程 我觉得很痛苦
it's physically painful watching you think.
我以为是你在拉小提琴
I thought it was you playing.
确实是我拉的
It was me playing.
我在作曲
I am composing.
你刚才在跳舞
You were dancing.
我刚才在做实地测试
I was road-testing.
你在干什么?
You what?
你怎么来了?
Why are you here?
我给你端了点早茶 你总是睡不醒
I'm bringing you your morning tea. You're not usually awake.
你还给我端早茶了?
You bring me tea in the morning?
对啊 不然你觉得它是从哪来的?
Well, where do you think it came from?
我不知道 我只是觉得它就这么出现了
I don't know. I just thought it sort of happened.
你母亲可要负很大责任
Your mother has a lot to answer for.
嗯 我知道 我有一清单的责任
Hmm, I know. I have a list.
麦考罗夫特的责任有一个文件夹那么多
Mycroft has a file.
今天是个大日子
So, it's the big day then.
什么大日子?
What big day?
婚礼! 约翰和玛丽要结婚了
The wedding! John and Mary getting married.
本来就生活在一起的两个人要进教堂
Two people who currently live together are about to attend church,
开派对 进行短途旅游 然后继续生活在一起
have a party, go on a short holiday, then carry on living together.
- 这样有什么重大可言?  - 婚姻会改变人生
- What's big about that?  - It changes people, marriage.
嗯 不 不会的
Hmm, no it doesn't.
你不懂的 因为你都是一个人生活
Well, you wouldn't understand, cos you always live alone.
你的丈夫因双重谋杀被处决
Your husband was executed for double murder.
你不可能是婚姻的支持者
You're hardly an advert for companionship.
婚姻用你无法想象的方式改变你的人生
Marriage changes you as a person in ways that you can't imagine.
注射处死也有同样的效果
As does lethal injection.
我最好的朋友玛格丽特 是我的首席伴娘
My best friend, Margaret, she was my chief bridesmaid,
我们过去总说 我们永远是最好的朋友
we were going to be best friends forever, we always said that,
但我结婚后就几乎没见过她
but I hardly saw her after that.
- 不是一般还有饼干吗?  - 吃完了
- Aren't there usually biscuits?  - I've run out.
店里也卖完了?
Have the shops?
她哭了一整天 说道"哦 过去一去不复返"
She cried the whole day, saying, "Ooh, it's the end of an era."
我确定拐角的商店是开的
I'm sure the shop on the corner is open.
她可能说对了 真的 我记得她走得很早
She was probably right, really. I remember she left early.
我是说 谁会在婚礼上早走呢? 真伤心
I mean, who leaves a wedding early? So sad.
嗯 不管怎样 你还有事要忙
Hmm. Anyway, you've got things to do.
- 没有 我有很多时间准备...  - 饼干!
- No, not really. I've got plenty of time to get ready...  - Biscuits!
哦! 我真的要去和你母亲谈一谈
Oh! I really am going to have a word with your mother.
如果你想的话可以 不过她基本不懂
You can if you like, she understands very little.
好了
Right then.
上战场了
Into battle.
恭喜!
Congratulations!
好 就站那儿 给新婚夫妇来张合影
OK, hold it there, I want to get this shot of the newlyweds.
呃 只有新郎和新娘 伴郎麻烦请让让
Er, just the bride and groom, please.
- 夏洛克...  - 哦 不好意思
- Sherlock...  - Oh, sorry.
好的 三 二 一 茄子
OK, three, two, one, cheese.
大名鼎鼎的福尔摩斯先生 很高兴认识你
The famous Mr Holmes. I'm very pleased to meet you.
- 不过不做爱 好吗?  - 什么?!
- But no sex, OK?  - Sorry?!
你别吓坏了 我只是开个玩笑
You don't have to look so scared, I'm only messing.
伴娘 伴郎 这是传统节目
Bridesmaid, best man, it's a bit traditional.
- 是吗?  - 不过不是必须的
- Is it?  - But not obligatory.
如果你想要来场艳遇 那边穿蓝衬衫的男人是最有可能成功的
If that's the sort of thing you're looking for, the man over there in blue is your best bet.
最近刚离婚的医生 有一只姜黄色的猫...
Recently divorced doctor with a ginger cat...
有一处改建房 曾经阳痿
a barn conversion and a history of erectile dysfunction.
考虑到这一点 可能不是你的最佳选择
Reviewing that information, possibly not your best bet.
对 可能不是
Yeah, maybe not.
不好意思 比我预想的多推理出了一点
Sorry, there was one more deduction there than I was expecting.
福尔摩斯先生 你会发挥非常大的作用的
Mr Holmes, you're going to be incredibly useful.
你好 很高兴见到你
Hello. Lovely to meet you.
- 你好  - 真漂亮 玛丽
- How are you?  - Beautiful, Mary.
- 谢谢  - 恭喜
- Thank you.  - Congratulations.
大卫!
David!
啊 玛丽 恭喜你 你看上去很美
Ah, ah, Mary. Congratulations, you look, um, very nice.
- 谢谢  - 约翰 恭喜你 你很幸运
- Thanks.  - John, congratulations. You're a lucky man.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 嗯 大卫 这是夏洛克  - 嗯
- Um, David, this is Sherlock.  - Hmm.
呃 我们... 我们已经见过了
Um, yeah, we've um... We've met.
那么 我做引导员具体是做什么?
So, what exactly are my duties as an usher?
我们先谈谈玛丽吧
Let's talk about Mary first.
不好意思 你说什么?
Sorry, what?
我想你知道我在说什么 你和玛丽谈过两年恋爱
Well, I think you know what. You went out with her for two years.
很多年前的事了 我们... 我们现在只是好朋友
Er, ages ago. We're... We're just good friends now.
那是个事实吗?
Is that a fact?
每次她发推特 你总在5分钟内回复 不论时间地点
Whenever she tweets, you respond within five minutes, regardless of time or current location,
这表明你设置她为短信提醒对象 在你的脸谱上关于这对新婚夫妇的照片里
suggesting you have her on text alert. In your Facebook photographs of the happy couple,
玛丽总在最中间 而约翰只出现半边或完全没出现
Mary takes centre frame, whereas John is always partly or entirely excluded.
你不能从那些就说我还对玛丽有兴趣...
Well, you can't assume from that I've still got some kind of interest in Mary...
你在至少三次不同的情况下 主动安抚玛丽
You volunteered to be a shoulder to cry on on no less than three separate occasions.
你还要辩护吗?
Do you have anything to say in your defence?
我想从现在起 你们会保持距离
I think from now on, we'll downgrade you to casual acquaintance.
每年会面不超过三次 都要经过事先计划
No more than three planned social encounters a year
而约翰每次都要在场
and always in John's presence.
我有你的联系方式 我会盯着你的
I have your contact details. I will be monitoring.
他们说得没错 你他妈就是个疯子
They're right about you. You're a bloody psychopath.
超强功能反社会人士 还有你的号码哦
High functioning sociopath, with your number.
嗯...
Um...
- 你好 亲爱的  - 谢谢
- Hello. Darling.  - Thank you.
- 你简直美翻了  - 谢谢
- You look fabulous.  - Thank you.
谢谢你能来 谢谢
Thanks for coming, thank you.
真棒 工作很出色 阿尔奇
Er, yes, well done in the service, Archie.
- 他真的变得开朗了 我不知道你怎么做到的  - 嗯...
- He's really come out of his shell. I don't know how you did it.  - Um...
基本上就是给新娘一个灿烂的微笑
Basically it's a cute smile to the bride's side,
- 给新郎一个灿烂的微笑 然后就拿出戒指  - 不要
- cute smile to the groom's side and then the rings.  - No.
- 你还得穿礼服  - 不要
- And you have to wear the outfit.  - No.
- 你真的得穿上礼服  - 为什么?
- You really do have to wear the outfit.  - What for?
- 成年人喜欢这样的东西  - 为什么?
- Grown-ups like that sort of thing.  - Why?
我不知道 我会找人问问
I don't know, I'll ask one.
你是个侦探
You're a detective.
- 没错  - 你侦破过谋杀案吗?
- Yep.  - Have you solved any murders?
- 当然 一大堆  - 我能看看吗?
- Sure, loads.  - Can I see?
好 没问题
Yeah, all right.
他眼睛里都是些什么东西?
What's all the stuff in his eye?
- 蛆  - 真酷!
- Maggots.  - Cool!
嗯
Hmm.
他说你会给他一些照片 作为奖励?
He said you had some pictures for him, as a treat?
对 如果他表现不错的话
Er, yes, if he's good.
- 砍头的照片  - 是个可爱的小村子
- Beheadings.  - Lovely little village.
嗯? 你刚才说了什么?
Hmm? What did you say?
笑一个
Hold it.
真棒
Nice.
- 我快饿疯了  - 谢了
- I'm starving.  - Thanks.
我减了好多斤 就为了塞进这条裙子里
I had to lose so much weight to get into this dress.
嗯 他看着不错
Hmm, he's nice.
有两款著名除臭剂的味道 都以强效出名
Traces of two leading brands of deodorant, both advertised for their strength,
表明他有狐臭 压力较大
suggestive of a chronic body odour problem, manifesting under stress.
好了 打住 他朋友呢?
OK, done there. What about his friend?
- 长期外遇 经常对妻子不忠  - 真的?
- Long-term relationship, compulsive cheat.  - Seriously?
他的智能手机用了防水外壳
Waterproof cover on his smart-phone.
但他的面色却表明他并不是做户外工作的
Yet his complexion doesn't indicate outdoor work.
这说明他习惯把手机带进浴室
It suggests he's in the habit of taking his phone into the shower with him,
- 也就是说他经常收一些短信和邮件 不想让老婆看见  - 我能选你吗?
- which means he often receives texts and emails he'd rather went unseen.  - Can I keep you?
- 你喜欢破案吗?  - 你有空吗?
- Do you like solving crimes?  - Do you have a vacancy?
- 哈利来了吗?  - 呃 没 还没来
- So, Harry?  - Er, no. No show.
亲爱的 真遗憾
Darling, I'm so sorry.
我觉得让她帮忙带话还是有点悬
Yeah, it was a bit of a punt asking her, I suppose.
不过自助式酒吧本来就不怎么靠谱
Still, free bar, wouldn't have been a good mix.
天啊 哇!
Oh. God, wow!
- 他就是...?  - 他来了
- Is that...?  - He came.
- 那就是他了 肖尔托少校  - 没错
- So that's him, Major Sholto.  - Uh-huh.
如果他们真是那么好的朋友 为什么他基本不提起他?
If they're such good friends, why does he barely even mention him?
他一直对我提起他 一提起就滔滔不绝
He mentions him all the time to me, never shuts up about him.
- 提起他?  - 对呀
- About him?  - Mm-hmm.
啊! 我怎么会选这种酒 真是难喝得要命!
Urgh! I chose this wine, it's bloody awful!
- 没错 确定他提起的就是他?  - 对呀
- Yes, but it's definitely him that he talks about?  - Mm-hmm.
非常非常高兴见到您 先生
I'm very, very, glad to see you, sir.
我知道你一般不参加这样的聚会
I know you don't really do this sort of thing.
我会参加老朋友的 华生
Well, I do for old friends, Watson.
约翰
John.
- 很高兴见到你  - 我也是
- It's good to see you.  - You too.
看来你挺适应社会生活的嘛
Civilian life suiting you, then?
- 呃 是吧 我想是吧 长官  - 不需要再去看心里医生了?
- Er, er, yes. Well, I think so, Sir.  - No more need for the trick cyclist?
不需要了 不过我还是时不时会去 算是调整心态
No, I go now and then. Sort of a top-up.
疗养很有帮助
Therapy can be very helpful.
这些年你住在哪?
Where are you living these days?
很偏僻的小地方 你不会知道的
Oh, way out in the middle of nowhere. You wouldn't know it.
- 你的气色不错...  - 我从来没听过他提起他的名字
- You look well...  - I've never even heard him say his name.
- 他基本上算隐居了 自从...  - 没错
- Well, he's almost a recluse, you know, since...  - Yes.
我本来以为他不会来的
I didn't think he'd show up at all.
约翰说他是他认识的最不爱社交的人了
John says he's the most unsociable man he's ever met.
- 是吗? 他是最不爱社交的?  - 嗯
- He is? He's the most unsociable?  - Hmm.
难怪他蹦蹦跳跳地像条小狗
Ah, that's why he's bouncing around him like a puppy.
哦 夏洛克!
Oh, Sherlock!
- 我们俩都不是他的初恋  - 别笑了
- Neither of us were the first, you know.  - Stop smiling.
今天可是我的大喜日子!
It's my wedding day!
呃!
Urgh!
喂? 怎么了 夏洛克?
Yes? What, Sherlock?
- 你怎么气喘吁吁的?  - 整理文件
- Why are you out of breath?  - Filing.
要么你正好被人挟持 要么就又在锻炼
Either I've caught you in a compromising position or you've been working out again.
- 我更倾向于后者  - 你有什么事?
- I favour the latter.  - What do you want?
我需要你回答我 迈克罗夫特 紧急情况
I need your answer, Mycroft, as a matter of urgency.
- 回答?  - 即使是最后时刻也不算太晚
- Answer?  - Even at the eleventh hour, it's not too late, you know.
天啊!
Oh, Lord!
你可以订车 私人飞机也随时待命
Cars can be ordered, private jets commandeered.
今天 就是今天了 对吗?
Today. It's today, isn't it?
不 夏洛克 我不会去那个晚上的活动的
No, Sherlock, I will not be coming to the night-do,
不管你怎么叫它
as you so poetically put it.
真可惜 玛丽和约翰肯定会非常...
What a shame. Mary and John will be extremely d...
非常高兴我没去乱转
Delighted not to have me hanging around.
不一定吧
Oh, I don't know.
宴会上总会有个幽灵
There should always be a spectre at the feast.
就是今天了? 婚礼的日子
So, this is it, then? The big day.
我猜从今天开始我能常常见到你了
I suppose I'll be seeing a lot more of you from now on.
- 你什么意思?  - 就像以前一样
- What do you mean?  - Just like old times.
- 我不懂  - 这是一个时代的终结 不是吗?
- No, I don't understand.  - Well, it's the end of an era, isn't it?
约翰和玛丽享受家庭的幸福
John and Mary, domestic bliss.
不 不 不 我更愿意把这当做是新篇章的开始
No, no, no. I prefer to think of it as the beginning of a new chapter.
- 怎么了?  - 没什么
- What?  - Nothing.
我知道那种沉默的意思 到底怎么了?
I know that silence. What?
我最好让你回去了
Well, I'd better let you get back to it.
你有个演讲之类的事要做 不是吗?
You have a big speech or something, don't you?
- 什么?  - 蛋糕加上唱歌
- What?  - Cakes, karaoke, mingling.
- 迈克罗夫特!  - 人们就是这样的 夏洛克 他们会结婚
- Mycroft!  - This is what people do, Sherlock. They get married.
我警告过你 别牵扯进去
I warned you, don't get involved.
- 牵扯进去? 我没有 - 没有吗...
- Involved? I'm not involved.  - No...
约翰让我给他当伴郎 我怎么能拒绝?
John asked me to be his best man, how could I say no?
- 是啊  - 我当然没有牵扯进去
- Absolutely.  - I'm not involved.
我相信你 真的
I believe you. Really, I do.
好好玩吧 把我的祝福带给那对幸福的新人
Have a lovely day and do give the happy couple my best.
我会的
I will.
顺便说问一句 夏洛克 你还记得"红胡子"吗?
Oh, by the way, Sherlock, do you remember Redbeard?
我不是小孩子了 迈克罗夫特
I'm not a child anymore, Mycroft.
你当然不是了
No, of course you're not.
好好享受不被牵扯去的感觉吧 夏洛克
Enjoy not getting involved, Sherlock.
请大家安静一下 伴郎要致辞了
Pray silence for the best man.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
家人和朋友们
family and friends,
还有...
and...
呃 其他人
um, others.
呃...
Er...
还... 还有...
A... also...
- 格雷格...  - 茉莉
- Greg...  - Molly.
我一直在想
I've just had a thought.
那是个大脑吗?
Is that a brain?
要是约翰让夏洛克当他的伴郎怎么办?
What if John asks Sherlock to be his best man?
- 他肯定会这样做的 不是吗? 他本来就是最好的  - 正是如此
- Well, he will, won't he? He's best.  - Exactly.
- 所以呢?  - 所以他就得在众人面前做一个演讲
- So?  - So, he'll have to make a speech, in front of people.
到时候会有真的人坐在那里 真的要听他说的话
There'll be actual people there, actually listening.
好吧 最坏的可能是什么?
Well, what's the worst that could happen?
海伦·路易斯也想问同样的问题
Helen Louise probably wondered the same.
那是谁?
Helen Louise?
嗨 亲爱的
Oh, hello dear.
我刚刚在想 如果约翰真的让夏洛克...
I was just thinking, if John does ask Sherlock...
什么 演讲? 不用担心 没事的
What, the speech, dear? No, it'll be fine.
可是不仅仅是演讲啊 不是吗?
It's not just the speech, though, is it?
真聪明!
Oh, brilliant!
- 哈德森太太?  - 嗨 亲爱的
- Mrs. Hudson?  - Hello, darling.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我是过来看望夏洛克的 然后我觉得你...
I was coming to see Sherlock and I thought you were...
- 没...  - 可能要挂了
- No...  - Possibly dying.
哦 抱歉
Oh, sorry.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
电报!
The telegrams!
不好意思 你说什么?
Sorry, what?
哦 抱歉
Oh, sorry.
电报!
Telegrams!
对了 呃...
Right, um...
首先是最重要的事 读电报
First things first, telegrams.
当然 它们不是真的电报 我们只是把它们叫做电报 我也不知道为什么
Well, they're not actually telegrams, we just call them telegrams. I don't know why.
可能是婚礼传统吧
Wedding tradition.
因为显然我们还没厌倦这传统
Because we don't have enough of that already, apparently.
"致华生夫妇
"To Mr and Mrs Watson,
非常抱歉我不能在你们大婚的日子陪在你们身旁
so sorry I am unable to be with you on your special day.
祝你们好运 一切顺利 麦克·斯坦福"
Good luck and best wishes, Mike Stanford."
"约翰和玛丽 祝你们新婚愉快
"To John and Mary, all good wishes for your special day,
请接受我的爱 以及许多大大的...
with love and many big...
来自史黛拉和泰德的黏糊糊的拥抱"
Big squishy cuddles from Stella and Ted."
"玛丽 我的小..."
"Mary, lots of love..."
嗯?
Yeah?
"小宝贝 请接受来自卡姆的满满的爱意和真挚的祝福"
"Poppet. Oodles of love and heaps of good wishes from Cam."
"希望你的家人也能在场"
"Wish your family could have seen this."
"特殊的日子..." "非常特殊的日子..."
"Special day..." "Very special day..."
"爱..." "爱..." "爱..." "爱..." "爱..."
"Love..." "Love..." "Love..." "Love..." "Love..."
主题都差不多 你知道我的意思吧 人们都挺喜欢说那些话的
Bit of a theme, you get the general gist. People are basically fond.
约翰·华生
John Watson.
我的朋友 约翰·华生
My friend, John Watson.
约翰...
John...
当约翰第一次说起让我当伴郎的时候 我有点没明白
When John first broached the subject of being best man, I was confused.
- 夏洛克?  - 楼下怎么那么吵?
- Sherlock?  - What was that noise downstairs?
哦 是哈德森太太在笑
Oh, it was Mrs. Hudson laughing.
哦 听起来像是她在折磨猫头鹰
Hmm, it sounded like she was torturing an owl.
好吧 不过那是笑声
Yeah, well, it was laughter.
都差不多
Could have been both.
在忙吗?
Busy?
就是分散下注意力 有时候觉得戒烟太难了
Oh, just occupying myself. Sometimes it's so hard not smoking.
介意我打断一下吗?
Mind if I interrupt?
请坐吧
Be my guest.
- 喝茶吗?  - 算了...
- Tea?  - Er...
好了 呃 说正事
So, er, the big question.
什么?
Mm-hmm?
伴郎
The best man.
最好的人?
The best man?
- 你觉得呢?  - 比利·金凯德
- What do you think?  - Billy Kincaid.
- 你说什么?  - 比利·金凯德 来自"卡姆登绞杀者" 他是我认识的最好的人了
- Sorry, what?  - Billy Kincaid, the Camden Garrotter, best man I ever knew.
为慈善事业做出巨大贡献 而且从不招摇
Vast contributions to charity, never disclosed.
他以一己之力使得三个医院没有倒闭
Personally managed to save three hospitals from closure
还经营着英国北部最好也最安全的孤儿院
and ran the best and safest children's homes in north England.
确实 现在他也还会绞死别人 不过他杀死的人相比于救过的人
Yes, every now and again there'd be some garrotings, but stacking up the lives saved against the garrotings,
- 我倒觉得他...  - 是我的婚礼
- on balance I'd say he...  - For my wedding.
是我 我需要一个伴郎
For me, I need a best man.
- 好吧  - 可能绞杀者不太好
- Oh, right.  - Maybe not a garrotter.
- 盖文怎么样?  - 谁?
- Gavin?  - Who?
盖文·雷斯垂德? 他是个男人 而且很善于这些事
Gavin Lestrade? He's a man and good at it.
他叫格雷格 但他不是我最好的朋友
It's Greg. And he's not my best friend.
我明白了 那就麦克·斯坦福
Oh, Mike Stanford, I see.
好吧 他挺好的 呃 不过我不确定他能不能对付...
Well, he's nice. Um, though I'm not sure how well he'd cope with all...
不 麦克很好 但他也不是我最好的朋友
No, Mike's great, but he's not my best friend.
听着 夏洛克 这是我人生中最重要的一天...
Look, Sherlock, this is the biggest and most important day of my life...
- 其实...  - 我不管 我说是就是
- Well...  - No, it is. It is.
所以我希望我在这世上最爱
And I want to be up there with the two people
- 也最在意的两个人都能在场  - 嗯
- that I love and care about most in the world.  - Yes.
- 一个是玛丽·摩斯坦  - 对啊
- So Mary Morstan...  - Yes.
还有就是...
And...
你
you.
我承认一开始我没意识到他是在邀请我当伴郎
I confess at first I didn't realise he was asking me.
当我明白过来的时候 我表现出了受宠若惊以及惊讶之情
When finally I understood, I expressed to him that I was both flattered and surprised.
我跟他解释 我完全没想到过这件事 而且我的表情有点像是被吓到了
I explained to him that I'd never expected this request and I was a little daunted in the face of it.
夏洛克...
Sherlock...
不过我也保证 我会尽我最大的努力完成这个 对我来说
I nonetheless promised I would do my very best to accomplish a task which was, for me,
和以往一样高难度的任务
as demanding and difficult as any I had ever contemplated.
除此之外 我很感谢他对我的信任 而且我
Additionally, I thanked him for the trust he placed in me and indicated that I was,
从某种程度上说 差点就要被感动了
in some ways, very close to being moved by it.
别这样 你有点吓人啊
No, it's getting a bit scary now.
后来事实证明这些我一个字都没说过
It later transpired that I'd said none of this out loud.
所以 其实...
So, in fact...
- 你 你是说...  - 对
- You, you mean...  - Yes.
我是你的...
I'm your...
最好的...
best...
- 伴郎...  - 朋友?
- Man...  - Friend?
是啊 你当然是了
Yeah, of course you are.
你当然... 是我最好的朋友
Of course... you're my best friend.
怎么样?
How was that?
感觉还不错
Surprisingly OK.
所以你显然得做个演讲
So you'll have to make a speech, of course.
说过了 说过了
Done that. Done that.
这个也差不多 那个算说过了吧
Done that bit, done that bit.
这个也说过了 嗯
Done that bit. Hmm.
约翰 恐怕我不能祝贺你
I'm afraid, John, I can't congratulate you.
所有的情感 尤其是爱情
All emotions, and in particular love,
都与我最重视的纯粹冷酷的理性相悖
stand opposed to the pure, cold reason I hold above all things.
在我看来 婚礼不过就是
A wedding is, in my considered opinion,
这个在道德妥协的世界对错误的 表面化的 非理性的
nothing short of a celebration of all that is false and specious and irrational
和情感上的事的庆祝罢了
and sentimental in this ailing and morally compromised world.
今天我们纪念的报死窃蠹就是我们社会最终的命运
Today we honour the deathwatch beetle that is the doom of our society,
而且很快 我敢肯定 整个人类社会都会如此
and in time, one feels certain, our entire species.
- 不过 不管怎么说 还是来说说约翰  - 请吧
- But anyway, let's talk about John.  - Please.
如果我让一个助手成为我冒险途中的负担
If I burden myself with a little helpmate during my adventures,
这并不是感情用事或者任性 而是因为他身上有许多优秀的品格
this is not out of sentiment or caprice, it is that he has many fine qualities of his own
而他自己都因为迷恋我而没有发现
that he has overlooked in his obsession with me.
其实 任何关于我思维敏捷清晰的声望都来自于
Indeed, any reputation I have for mental acuity and sharpness comes, in truth,
出色的约翰为我做出的无的奉献
from the extraordinary contrast John so selflessly provides.
事实上 我觉得今天的新娘比较喜欢特别平庸的伴娘
It is a fact, I believe, that brides tend to favour exceptionally plain bridesmaids for their big day.
这是个类比 不过不同的是
There is a certain analogy there, I feel. And contrast is, after all,
上帝会加强他所造之物的美丽
God's own plan to enhance the beauty of his creation.
否则上帝就是个用来给家里的白痴
Or it would be if God were not a ludicrous fantasy
提供就业机会的可笑幻想了
designed to provide a career opportunity for the family idiot.
我想说的是 我是个
The point I'm trying to make is that I am
最招人烦 最粗鲁无礼
the most unpleasant, rude,
自大傲慢 十恶不赦的混蛋
ignorant and all-round obnoxious arsehole
任何人遇到我都算是不幸
that anyone could possibly have the misfortune to meet.
我蔑视美德
I am dismissive of the virtuous,
忽视美丽
unaware of the beautiful
而且不能理解快乐的表情
and uncomprehending in the face of the happy.
所以如果我不能明白被邀请作为伴郎是什么意思
So if I didn't understand I was being asked to be best man,
那是因为我从没想到过 我能成为别人最好的朋友
it is because I never expected to be anybody's best friend.
而且当然不可能是
And certainly not the best friend
这世上我遇到过的 最勇敢善良有智慧的人的好朋友
of the bravest and kindest and wisest human being
遇到他是我最大的幸运
I have ever had the good fortune of knowing.
约翰 我是个古怪的人
John, I am a ridiculous man.
只能被你长久以来温暖的友情感化
Redeemed only by the warmth and constancy of your friendship.
不过 虽然我是你最好的朋友
But, as I am apparently your best friend,
我不能为你选择的伴侣而祝贺你
I cannot congratulate you on your choice of companion.
其实 我想我能
Actually, now I can.
玛丽 当我说你配得上这个男人的时候
Mary, when I say you deserve this man,
这就是我能给予你的最高的赞美了
it is the highest compliment of which I am capable.
约翰 你经历过战争 伤痛 还失去过重要的人...
John, you have endured war and injury and tragic loss...
我再次为那件事道歉... 所以你要知道 今天你正坐在
so sorry again about that last one... so know this, today you sit between
你的夫人和你拯救过的人之间
the woman you have made your wife and the man you have saved.
也就是这世界上最爱你的两个人了
In short, the two people who love you most in all this world.
而且我知道我可以代表玛丽说
And I know I speak for Mary as well when I say,
我们绝不会让你失望 而且我们会用一辈子去证明这一点
we will never let you down and we have a lifetime ahead to prove that.
- 要是我想拥抱他 拦住我  - 我才不呢
- If I try and hug him, stop me.  - Certainly not.
啊 好了 现在来说说有关约翰的趣事吧
Ah, yes. Now onto some funny stories about John.
怎么了? 什么情况? 你们都怎么了? 约翰?
What's wrong? What happened? Why are you all doing that? John?
夏洛克!
Oh, Sherlock!
- 我出错了吗?  - 不 没有 来吧
- Did I do it wrong?  - No, you didn't. Come here.
- 我还没说完呢  - 是 我知道 知道
- I haven't finished yet.  - Yeah, I know, I know.
- 那么我们来说点有趣的事...  - 能不能至少等我坐下再说?
- So onto some funny stories now...  - Can you wait till I sit down?
来说点有关约翰的趣闻轶事
So, onto some funny stories about John.
你们要是能开心点就再好不过了
If you could all just cheer up a bit, that would be better.
这就对了
On we go.
好玩的事 不能不说说约翰的博客
So for funny stories, one has to look no further than John's blog.
我们共同生活的记录
The record of our time together.
当然 他有点夸张了
Of course, he does tend to romanticise things a bit,
不过 大家都知道 他本来就是个爱幻想的家伙
but then, you know, he's a romantic.
我们处理了一些奇怪的案子
We've tackled some strange cases.
空心客户...
The Hollow Client...
毒巨人...
The Poison Giant...
低头 约翰!
Get down, John!
也有过一些令人沮丧的案子...
We've had some frustrating cases...
那是什么?
What is that?
有一个法国十项全能运动员疯了 被发现的时候
A French decathlete found completely out of his mind,
他的身边有1821个火柴盒
surrounded by 1,812 matchboxes,
除了这个都是空的
all empty except this one.
这个里面有什么?
And what's in that one?
难以言表
Inexplicable.
有令人感动的案件...
Touching cases...
她要按门铃了
She's going to ring the doorbell.
不 她改变主意了
Oh, no. She's changed her mind.
她又要来按了 她反悔了
Oh, she's going to do it. No, she's leaving.
她走了 她又回来了
She's leaving. Oh, she's coming back.
- 她是个无聊的客户 我以前见过这情况  - 然后?
- She's a client, she's boring. I've seen those symptoms before.  - Hmm?
在街道上徘徊通常意味着是爱情方面的问题
Oscillation on the pavement always means there's a love affair.
当然还要提一下房间里的大象...
And of course I have to mention the elephant in the room...
在这个特殊的日子
But we want something
应该要分享些特殊事件 不是吗?
very particular for this special day, don't we?
浴血卫兵...
The Bloody Guardsman...
(浴血卫兵)
玛丽 你忙着结婚的事都瘦了
Need to work on your half of the church, Mary, looking a bit thin.
孤儿没什么其它东西 我也就只有朋友多了
Oh, orphan's lot. Friends, that's all I have, lots of friends.
电子琴表演要在十一点四十八分开始...
Schedule the organ music to begin at precisely 11:48...
但彩排得是两周之后的事了 冷静点
But the rehearsal's not for another two weeks, just calm down.
冷静? 我很冷静啊
Calm? I am calm. I'm extremely calm.
我们来安排座位
Let's get back to the reception, come on.
约翰的表姐 主桌?
John's cousin, top table?
她讨厌你 连想都不愿想到你
Hmm, hates you. Can't even bear to think about you.
- 真的?  - 平邮 廉价明信片
- Seriously?  - Second class post, cheap card.
在加油站买的 看看邮票 舔了三下贴上的
Bought at a petrol station. Look at the stamp, three attempts at licking,
显然没意识到留下了口水
she's obviously unconsciously retaining saliva.
- 让她坐厕所旁边好了  - 好的
- Ah, let's stick her by the bogs.  - Oh, yes.
还有谁讨厌我?
Who else hates me?
好的 谢谢
Oh, great, thanks.
"无价之画被偷" 很有趣的样子
"Priceless painting nicked." Looks interesting.
- 四号桌...  - 已经好了
- Table four...  - Done.
"我的丈夫有三个"
"My husband is three people."
- 五号桌...  - 詹姆斯·肖尔托少校 他是谁?
- Table five...  - Major James Sholto, who he?
- 约翰以前的指挥官 我觉得他不会来  - 他会来的
- John's old commanding officer. I don't think he's coming.  - He'll be there.
- 他没回复啊  - 他会来的
- Well, he needs to RSVP, then.  - He'll be there. Oh.
"我的丈夫有三个" 很有趣啊
"My husband is three people." It's interesting.
说他有三种不一样的痣
It says he has three distinct patterns of moles on his skin.
三胞胎 百万分之一的出生率 足不出户就解决了
Identical triplets, one in half a million births. Solved it without leaving the flat.
餐巾... 要天鹅的还是悉尼歌剧院的?
Now, serviettes... Swan or Sydney Opera House?
- 你哪学的这些?  - 犯罪调查需要很多技巧...
- Where did you learn that?  - Many skills are required in the field of criminal investigation...
- 骗人 夏洛克  - 我有次通过餐巾的折纸来破案...
- Fibbing, Sherlock.  - I once broke an alibi by demonstrating the exact severity of a fold...
- 我不是约翰 我知道你在撒谎  - 好吧 我在YouTube上学的
- I'm not John, I can tell when you're fibbing.  - OK, I learnt it on YouTube.
悉尼歌剧院 等等 我有电话
Opera House, please. Oh, hang on, I'm buzzing.
喂?
Hello?
哦 你好 贝丝
Oh, hi, Beth.
没事 没有什么不可以
Yeah, yeah, I don't see why not.
如果是贝丝 恐怕我得去一下 等等
Actually, if that's Beth, it's probably for me too, hang on.
他知道我们没有叫贝丝的朋友 他马上就会意识到这是暗号
He knows we don't have a friend called Beth, he's going to figure out that it's code.
- 他竟然在网上学叠餐巾  - 他考虑很周全
- He's YouTubing serviettes.  - He's thorough.
- 他吓坏了  - 他才没有
- He's terrified.  - Of course he's not.
当你害怕一件事的时候 你就会希望它快点结束 通通做完
When you're scared of something you start wishing it sooner, just to get it all going.
他为什么要害怕我们结婚?
But why would he be scared that we're getting married?
不会改变任何事的 我们还是会一起破案
It's not going to change anything, we'll still do stuff.
你得证明给他看 我跟你说了 给他找个案子
You need to prove it to him. I told you to find him a new case.
- 我在努力了  - 你得催促他 给他看看你们曾经的美好时光
- I'm trying.  - But you need to run him, OK? Show him it's still the good old days.
随便就叠好了
That just sort of happened.
夏洛克 嗯 伙计...
Sherlock, um, mate...
我...
I have...
我闻了十八种不同的香水
I've smelled 18 different perfumes,
试吃了九种不同的蛋糕 都差不多
I've sampled nine different slices of cake, which all tasted identical.
我希望伴娘穿紫色...
I like the bridesmaids in purple...
- 丁香紫  - 是的
- Lilac.  - Lilac.
没有其它什么要准备的了
Um, there are no more decisions left to make.
我还不明白我们做的这些决定
I don't even understand the decisions that we have made.
我骗人很累的
I'm faking opinions, and it's exhausting.
请在她回来之前... 找点事做
So, please, before she comes back... pick something.
- 随便选一个  - 选什么?
- Anything. Pick one.  - Pick what?
案子 你收件箱要爆了
A case. Your inbox is bursting.
就... 帮我一下
Just... get me out of here.
你想要我现在去破案? 现在吗?
You want to go out on a case? Now?
求你了 夏洛克
Please. Sherlock, for me.
别担心了 我会帮你的
Don't you worry about a thing, I'll get you out of this.
哦
Oh.
"福尔摩斯先生 我叫本布瑞吉
"Dear Mr Holmes, my name is Bainbridge.
我是女王私人住宅的卫兵
I'm a Private in Her Majesty's Household Guard.
我写信给你是为了一件私事...
I'm writing to you about a personal matter...
我不想跟我上司说这件事
one I don't care to bring before my superiors,
听上去很普通
it would sound so trivial.
我觉得有人在跟踪我
But I think someone's stalking me.
我对参观者已经习以为常了
I'm used to tourists, it's part of the job,
但是这个人不一样
but this is different.
他监视我
Someone's watching me.
每天都来拍我的照片
He's taking pictures of me every day.
我不想跟少校说起 但是这真的很扰人"
I don't want to mention it to the Major, but it's really preying on my mind."
制服脑残粉? 所有的好姑娘都喜欢士兵
Uniform fetishist? All the nice girls like a soldier.
是"水手" 而且他认为跟踪他的是个男人
It's "sailor". And Bainbridge thinks his stalker is a bloke.
我们去查查吧
Let's go and investigate. Please.
- 精英卫兵  - 在职的有40名卫兵及官员
- Elite guard.  - 40 enlisted men and officers.
为什么非是他? 真奇怪
Why this particular Grenadier? Curious.
你说了算
Now you're talking.
- 去吧  - 再见!
- OK.  - Bye!
呃 我们准备去... 我需要夏洛克帮我
Er, we're just going to... I need, um, Sherlock to help me
- 选... 领带  - 袜子
- choose some er... ties.  - Socks.
- 要不买袜子吧?  - 好的
- Why don't we go with socks?  - Yeah.
我是说你必须选双好看点的
I mean, you've got to get the right ones.
- 是的 现在去拿... 领带  - 外套
- Exactly, to go with my... Tie.  - Outfit.
要一会 是吗?
That'll take a while, right?
- 我大衣在那吗?  - 是的
- Is my coat in there?  - Yes.
我要带他出去一会 帮他鼓鼓劲
I'm just going to take him out for a bit. Run him.
- 我懂 你说过要给他找个案子  - 嗯
- I know. You said you'd find him a case.  - Hmm.
- 可以走了吗 夏洛克?  - 来了!
- Coming, Sherlock?  - Coming!
出租车!
Taxi!
立定!
Company halt!
向右转!
Right turn!
我们来见史蒂芬·本布瑞吉二等兵
We're here to see Private Stephen Bainbridge.
他在站岗 先生
He's on duty right now, sir.
他空闲了我会通知你
But I'll certainly let him know when he's free.
大概要多久?
And when will that be?
一个小时
Another hour.
你觉得他们给他上过课吗?
Do you think they give them classes?
课?
Classes?
怎样抵制想要挠后面的冲动
How to resist the temptation to scratch their behinds.
传入末梢神经的神经冲动
Afferent neurons in the peripheral nervous system.
屁股痒
Bum-itch.
哦
Oh.
你为什么不再见他了?
So why don't you see him any more?
- 谁?  - 你的前指挥官肖尔托
- Who?  - Your previous commander, Sholto.
前指挥官?
Previous commander?
我是说前任
I meant ex.
"前"标明我现在还有长官
"Previous" suggests that I currently have a commander.
- 我现在没有  - 我没有
- Which you don't.  - Which I don't.
你当然没有
Of course you don't.
他被表彰了 是吗? 战争英雄?
He was decorated, wasn't he? A war hero?
不是每个人都是
Not to everyone.
他带领一支小队去了战地
He led a team of crows into battle.
小队?
Crows?
新兵 入伍必要程序
New recruits. It's standard procedure break the new boys in.
但是出事了
But it went wrong.
他们都死了 他是唯一的幸存者
They all died, he was the only survivor.
- 来自死者家庭和媒体的压力不断 他收到的死亡威胁比你还多  - 我可没数过
- The press and families gave him hell, he gets more death threats than you.  - Oh, I wouldn't count on that.
你为什么突然对另一个人感兴趣了?
And why have you suddenly taken an interest in another human being?
我在"聊天"
I'm "chatting".
不会再发生了
I won't be trying that again.
改变主题...
Changing the subject completely...
我和玛丽结婚不会改变一切的 你明白吧?
you know it won't alter anything, right, me and Mary getting married?
我们还是会一起破案
We'll still be doing all this.
- 真好  - 我怕你担心
- Oh, good.  - If you were worried.
我不担心
I wasn't worried.
哼
Hmm.
说到玛丽
The thing about Mary,
她彻底改变了我的生活
she has completely turned my life around.
改变了一切
Changed everything.
但你得明白
But, for the record,
过去这几年里 只有两个人做到了
over the last few years there are two people who have done that,
而这另一个...
and the other one is...
是个十足的混蛋
a complete dickhead.
我能问这有什么联系吗?
Can I ask what this is in connection with?
本布瑞吉二等兵联系我们帮他解决私事 长官
Private Bainbridge contacted us about a personal matter, Sir.
在我的军队里没有私事
Nothing's personal when it concerns my troops.
你到底想要什么?
What do you really want?
我来替他请假
I'm here on a legitimate enquiry.
你是媒体的人吗? 想挖一些皇家的八卦新闻?
Are you press? Digging for some bloody Royal story or something?
不会 长官 我是约翰华生上尉
No, Sir, I'm Captain John Watson,
第五诺森伯兰炮兵团的
Fifth Northumberland Fusiliers.
退伍了
Retired.
据我所知 你可能只是个二手车推销员
You could be a used-car salesman now, for all I know.
本布瑞吉?
Bainbridge?
有人要见你
Gentleman here to see you.
本布瑞吉!
Bainbridge!
我认识你 是吗?
I know you, don't I?
嗯?
Hmm?
我在报纸上见过你
I've seen you in the papers.
你跟一个带着蠢帽子的
You hang around with that detective,
侦探到处混
the one with the silly hat.
本布瑞吉到底找侦探要干嘛?
What the hell does Bainbridge want with a detective?
我没权力告诉你
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty to say.
你没权力? 他是我的士兵
You're not at liberty to say? He's a soldier in my regiment.
- 他穿着制服做些没意义的事 我就倒霉了  - 长官!
- I'll be damned if he's going to get up to cloak-and-dagger nonsense like this.  - Sir!
- 怎么了?  - 是本布瑞吉 长官
- What's going on?  - It's Bainbridge, sir.
他死了
He's dead.
天啊!
My God!
让我看一眼 我是医生
Ah! No, let me take a look, sir, I'm a doctor.
什么?
What?
中士 逮捕他!
Sergeant, arrest this man!
什么? 不 不! 我是医生!
What? No, no! I'm a doctor!
你现在又是医生了? 中士
Oh, you're a doctor now too? Sergeant.
请让我看看!
Let me examine him, please!
抓到个偷偷四处转悠的 长官
Sir, caught this one snooping around.
这就是你们的计划?
Is that what this is all about?
分散我的注意力 所以他能混进来
Distracting me, so that this man could get in here
- 杀死本布瑞吉?  - 别...
- and kill Bainbridge?  - Don't be...
- 用什么杀他? 凶器在哪?  - 什么?
- Kill him with what? Where's the weapon?  - What?
凶器在哪? 随便搜 没有凶器
Where's the weapon? Go on, search me, no weapon.
本布瑞吉在站岗 他五分钟前刚下班
Bainbridge was on parade, he came off duty five minutes ago.
怎么可能是我们下的手?
When's this supposed to have happened?
- 你肯定在他洗澡前就捅死了他  - 没有
- You obviously stabbed him before he got into the shower.  - No.
- 没有?!  - 他浑身湿透 头发上还有洗发水 是他进去洗澡后才被捅的
- No?!  - He's soaking wet and there's shampoo in his hair. He got into the shower, then someone stabbed him.
隔间是从里面被锁住的 长官 玻璃是我打破的
The cubicle was locked from the inside, sir. I had to break it open.
- 你一定是从上面爬进去的  - 这样我也浑身湿透了 不是吗?
- You must have climbed over the top.  - But then I'd be soaking wet too, wouldn't I?
少校! 我是约翰·华生 第五诺森伯兰炮兵团
Major, please! I'm John Watson, Fifth Northumberland Fusiliers,
在阿富汗驻守三年 在坎大哈 赫尔曼德
three years in Afghanistan, a veteran of Kandahar, Helmand
巴特医院工作过的资深医生!
and Bart's bloody Hospital!
让我去尸检!
Let me examine this body!
谢谢
Thank you.
自杀?
Suicide?
不 没有凶器 没有刀
No. The weapon again, no knife.
腹部有一处伤口
Now, there is a wound to the abdomen.
很好
Incredibly fine.
被刺死 没有凶器
Man stabbed to death, no murder weapon.
门从里面锁住
Door locked from the inside.
- 出入口只有一个  - 夏洛克...
- Only one way in or out of here.  - Sherlock...
- 嗯?  - 他还有呼吸
- Hmm?  - He's still breathing.
天啊!
Oh, my God!
- 现在怎么办?  - 给我围巾
- What do we do?  - Give me your scarf.
- 什么?  - 快点! 叫救护车!
- What?  - Quickly, now! Call an ambulance!
- 什么?  - 叫救护车!
- What?  - Call an ambulance, now!
快去!
Do it!
护士 用力按住这里
Nurse, press here, hard.
- 护士?  - 是的 快点
- Nurse?  - Yeah, I'm making do.
压住伤口
Keep pressure on that wound.
史蒂芬? 史蒂芬 坚持住
Stephen? Stephen, stay with me.
本布瑞吉二等兵刚站完岗
Private Bainbridge had just come off guard duty.
他在那站了四个小时 很多人都看到了
He'd stood there for hours, plenty of people watching,
没有什么奇怪的事情
nothing apparently wrong.
下班几分钟后却因为腹部的一个伤口
He came off duty and within minutes was nearly dead
差点死掉
from a wound in his stomach,
但没有凶器
but there was no weapon.
凶器去哪了?
Where did it go?
女士们 先生们 我请你们想一下...
Ladies and gentlemen, I invite you to consider this...
凶手如何穿墙逃走
a murderer who can walk through walls,
凶器又如何凭空消失
a weapon that can vanish.
但在这之中 有一个细节格外值得注意
But in all of this, there is only one element which can be said to be truly remarkable.
有人猜到是什么吗?
Would anyone like to make a guess?
快点 快点
Come on, come on,
其实答案已经在其中了
there is actually an element of Q&A to all of this.
苏格兰场的 你有想法吗?
Scotland Yard, have you got a theory?
是啊 你其实也算半个侦探了 有想法吗?
Yeah, you, you're a detective, broadly speaking. Got a theory?
嗯 如果...
Er, um, if the, er...
如果... 如果...
If the... If the...
如果凶器能从...
If the blade was propelled through the, erm...
通风口的栅栏里伸出来的话
grating in the air vent,
比如弩箭或者弹弓...
maybe a ballista or a catapult, um...
体型小的人就能爬进通风口里作案
Somebody tiny could crawl in there.
所以 凶手可能是个侏儒
So, yeah, we're looking for a dwarf.
聪明
Brilliant.
- 我说对了?  - 没有
- Really?  - No.
还有谁?
Next?
他是自杀
He stabbed himself.
谁 是谁说的?
Hello, who was that?
汤姆?
Tom?
有想法吗?
Got a theory?
我猜是自杀 凶器是压缩的骨头和血
Attempted suicide, with a blade made of compacted blood and bone.
刺穿自己腹部之后就碎掉了
Broke after piercing his abdomen,
比如用肉做的...
like a meat...
匕首
dagger.
肉做的匕首?
A meat dagger?
- 对  - 快坐下
- Yes.  - Sit down.
不对
No.
在这件棘手的案件中 有一件事
There was one feature, and only one feature, of interest
只有一个细节很有意思
in the whole of this baffling case,
坦白地说 那就是平日里的约翰·华生
and quite frankly it was the usual John Watson.
在我寻找线索的时候 他却已经拯救了一个生命
Who, while I was trying to solve a murder, instead saved a life.
虽然有很多怪案值得我思索
There are mysteries worth solving
也很多故事值得我讲述
and stories worth telling.
但是这个我认识的最勇敢的人
The best and bravest man I know
真正知道如何做有意义的事
and, on top of that, he actually knows how to do stuff.
除了准备婚礼和布置现场 他不在行这些
Except wedding planning and serviettes, he's rubbish at those.
这个案件至今仍是
Hmm. The case itself remains
我有幸遇到过的 最有创意的
the most ingenious and brilliantly planned murder, or attempted murder,
也是最精巧的谋杀 或者自杀
I've ever had the pleasure to encounter.
这是我所见识的最完美的密室案件
The most perfect locked-room mystery of which I am aware.
然而 我在这里不仅要称赞约翰
However, I'm not just here to praise John,
我也要让他羞愧一下 现在我们来讲讲...
I'm also here to embarrass him, so let's move on to...
不 等一下... 那案件到底是怎么回事?
No, wait... How was it done?
- 什么怎么回事?  - 他怎么被刺的?
- How was what done?  - The stabbing?
很抱歉我不知道
I'm afraid I don't know.
那案子我没破成
I didn't solve that one.
我有时也会想不明白 非常非常遗憾
It can happen sometimes, it's very, very disappointing.
说起来羞愧 我要讲一讲告别单身庆祝的事
Embarrassment leads me on to the stag night.
当然 整件事情能说上几小时
Of course there's hours of material here,
我只讲精彩的部分
but I've cut it down to the really good bits.
(蜉蝣男)
凶案现场在哪?
Murder scenes?
谋杀现场在哪?
Locations of murders?
嗯 其实是我们要去扫各种主题酒吧
Hmm, pub crawl, themed.
噢 你们怎么不去地铁站呢?
Yeah, but why can't you just do Underground stations?
那地方没有感觉 我们要去每一个...
It lacks the personal touch. We're going to go for a drink in every...
每一个你发现过尸体的街上喝酒 真有兴致!
In every street where you've found a corpse. Delightful!
要我帮什么忙?
Where do I come in?
我不想喝出毛病 影响心情
Don't want to get ill. That would ruin it, spoil the mood.
你是化学研究生 就自己不能做实验分析?
You're a graduate chemist, can't you just work it out?
我没有实际经验
I lack the practical experience.
- 你是说我爱喝酒?  - 偶尔会喝
- Meaning you think I like a drink?  - Occasionally.
- 我是个酒鬼?  - 不... 不
- That I'm a drunk.  - No... No.
你看上去... 还不错
You look... well.
我是好
I am.
汤姆...
How's...
怎么样?
Tom?
至少不是反社会人格
Not a sociopath.
还没犯病? 很好
Still? Good.
我们做爱很多次了
And we're having quite a lot of sex.
好吧 我想让你计算约翰和我的酒量
OK. I want you to calculate John's ideal intake, and mine,
好让整晚度得甜蜜一点
to remain in the sweet spot for the whole evening.
头晕... 还行
Light-headed... good.
在衣柜里小便... 不好
Urinating in wardrobes... bad.
嗯
Hmm.
两瓶... 啤酒 谢谢
Two, erm... beers, please.
大杯?
Pints?
443.7毫升
443.7 millilitres.
啊
Ah.
怎么 都计划好了?
What, are we on a schedule?
你会感谢我的
You'll thank me.
- 干杯  - 干杯
- Cheers.  - Cheers.
- 在那边  - 什么?
- Over there.  - What?
厕所... 现在你随时都会想要去...
Toilets... any second now you're going to need...
- 等一下再告诉我 我想上厕所  - 嗯 我都算好了
- Hang on, tell me after. I need the loo.  - Hmm, on schedule.
- 嗯?  - 没事 走吧!
- Eh?  - Nothing. Go!
- 多长时间?  - 什么?
- How long?  - Sorry?
你去了多久
Your visit.
估算大约排放量...
Estimate approximate volume discharge...
别说了
Stop talking now.
噢 快点 再来一杯 别让他看见
Oh, quick, one more. He mustn't see.
给你 干杯
Here you go. Cheers.
我连烟灰都研究! 别说我不懂!
I know ash! Don't tell me I don't!
好了 够了! 赶紧... 老实站着
All right, enough! That's... Stand up.
烟灰 我懂烟灰
Ash. I know ash.
我在国际上有声誉
I have an international reputation.
你也有国际声誉吗?
Do you have an international reputation?
- 不 我没有国际声誉  - 没有
- No, I don't have an international reputation.  - No.
我想不起来是为什么了
And I can't even remember what for.
犯罪... 还是其他什么
It's crime... something or other.
噢 你俩回来干什么?
Oh, what are you doing back?
我以为你们要很晚回来呢
I thought you were going to be up late.
哈德太太 现在几点了?
Ah, Hudders. What time is it?
你们只出去了两小时
You've only been out two hours.
(夏洛克  福尔摩斯)
(麦当娜)
我是蔬菜吗?
Am I a vegetable?
你 还是... 它?
You or the... thing?
有意思!
Funny!
谢谢
Thank you.
- 快说  - 不 你不是蔬菜
- Come on.  - No, you're not a vegetable.
该你了
It's your go.
嗯...
Erm...
我是人吗?
am I human?
有时吧
Sometimes.
不能说有时
Can't have sometimes.
必须是 嗯...
It has to be, um...
- 是 你是人  - 对 我知道 好吧 我是男的吗?
- Yes, you're human.  - Yes, I know, OK. And am I a man?
- 对  - 长得高吗?
- Yep.  - Tall?
没人们想象中那么高
Not as tall as people think.
嗯 人好吗?
Hmm. Nice?
还行
Ish.
聪明吗?
Clever?
我想是
I would say so.
你想是
You would.
嗯 我重要吗?
Hmm, am I important?
对一些人来说是
To some people.
人们喜欢我吗?
Do people like me?
嗯 不 不喜欢
Erm, no they don't.
你有时候让人觉得尴尬
You tend to rub them up the wrong way.
好吧
OK.
我是现任英国国王吗?
Am I the current King of England?
咱们哪里有国王
You know we don't have a King.
- 没有国王?  - 没有
- Don't we?  - No.
该你了
Your go.
不管了 我是女的吗?
I don't mind. Am I a woman?
是吗?
What?
是
Yes.
我... 漂亮吗?
Am I... pretty?
这人?
This?
审美观完全是由童年时 一个人对模范的印象
Beauty is a construct based entirely on childhood impressions,
和所受到的影响造成的
influences and role models.
是啊 那我漂亮吗?
Yeah, but am I a pretty lady?
我不认识你 我不知道你长什么样
I don't know who you are, I don't know who you're supposed to be.
是你选的名字!
You picked the name!
但我是从报纸上乱选的
But I picked it at random from the papers.
你其实不会玩这个游戏吧 夏洛克?
You're not really getting the hang of this game, are you, Sherlock?
我是人 我没有人们想象中高 我...
So I am human, I'm not as tall as people think I am. I'm...
我人品还算好 聪明
I'm nice-ish, clever,
对一些人来说很重要
important to some people.
但我有时会让他们觉得尴尬
But I tend to rub them up the wrong way.
我猜到了
Got it.
- 是谁  - 我是你 对吧?
- Go on, then.  - I'm you, aren't I?
有客户!
Client!
你好
Hello.
- 你好  - 进来吧
- Hello.  - Come on.
你们哪位是夏洛克·福尔摩斯?
Which one of you is Sherlock Holmes?
我没有...
I don't... a lot.
我从没怎么约会过
I mean, I don't date all that much.
他看起来挺不错的
And he seemed nice, you know.
我们心有灵犀
We seemed to automatically connect.
我们晚上出去约会
We had one night,
然后吃饭 谈得很投缘
dinner, such interesting conversation.
那晚很浪漫
It was lovely.
说实话
To be honest,
我还想继续交往下去
I'd love to have gone further,
但我想 不 这是恋爱
but I thought, no, this is special,
慢慢来吧
let's take it slowly.
然后我们交换了电话
Exchanged numbers,
他说他会继续联系我 结果...
he said he'd get in touch and then...
大概 他不像我一样渴望这份感情吧
Maybe he wasn't quite as keen as I was,
但我只想
but I just thought
他至少应该给我打一个分手电话吧
at least he'd call to say that we were finished.
我去了他家
I went round there,
他的公寓 完全找不见他
to his flat, no trace of him.
福尔摩斯先生 我真觉得
Mr Holmes, I honestly think
自己在和鬼魂约会
I had dinner with a ghost.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr Holmes?
和鬼魂约会 福尔摩斯先生!
With a ghost, Mr Holmes!
无聊 无聊 无聊... 不...
Boring, boring, boring... No...
精彩极了
fascinating.
约翰 约翰! 醒醒
John. John! Wake up.
我非常抱歉 我的... 他...
I apologise about my... You know... Him.
注意礼貌 礼貌!
Rude. Rude!
我向房主打听
I checked with the landlord
结果发现住在那的人早就死了
and the man who lived there died.
心脏病发作
Heart attack.
可我们居然一起吃了一星期的晚饭
And there we are having dinner one week on.
然后我在网上
And I found this thing online,
发现了这个聊天室
a sort of chatroom thing,
里面都些是发现自己和鬼魂约会的女孩
for girls who think they're dating men from the spirit world.
别担心 十分钟之内我就帮你找出来
Don't worry, I'll find him in ten minutes.
你刚说你的狗叫什么来着?
What's your dog's name?
- 啊 你叫我随时就到...  - 约翰 快醒醒
- Yeah, I'm there if you want it...  - John, wake up.
做梦呢... 好了
Went to... Yeah.
游戏... 怎么来着
The game is... something.
开始?
On?
对 对 开始
Yeah, that, that.
好的
OK.
噢 很不错
Oh, it's nice.
这房子不错
Nice place.
- 发现什么了吗?  - 嗯?
- See anything?  - Hmm?
有什么线索吗 福尔摩斯先生?
Any clues, Mr Holmes?
(名家出品 桌子 艺术?)
(椅子 座位 皮毛 睡觉)
(发言人 事件 电子狂人)
(死亡? 头骨? 去世?)
(木头? 无名氏? 烟斗/管子/匿名者)
(鸡蛋? 椅子? 用来坐的?)
(护士? 毛衣外套 顾客 受害人?)
先容我把外套脱了
I'm just going to whip this out.
- 你没事吧?  - 恩? 没事 他在找线索
- You all right?  - Hmm? Yeah, he's clueing.
什么?
What?
他... 恩? 他在找线索
He's... Hmm? He's clueing for looks.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr Holmes?
- 福尔摩斯先生!  - 我要叫警察了
- Mr Holmes!  - I'm calling the police.
别...
Oh, no...
等等 别动!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
听着 这位是著名侦探
No, look, this is a famous detective,
夏洛克·福尔摩斯 以及他的助手约翰·哈米什·华生
it's Sherlock Holmes and his partner, John Hamish Watson.
你知道自己在做什么吗?
What do you think you're doing?
不要
Don't compromise
破坏...
the integrity of the...
犯罪现场
Crime scene.
说得对
Yeah, that.
醒醒!
Wakey-wakey!
天啊
Oh, my God.
格雷格... 是格雷格吗?
Greg... Is that Greg?
起来 我得把你俩扔进出租车里
Get up. I'm going to put you two in a taxi.
我跟接待警员谈妥了事情
I managed to square things with the desk sergeant.
哈! 两个不知轻重的家伙
Ha! What a couple of lightweights,
你们居然没撑到关门!
you couldn't even make it to closing time!
- 你能小点声不?  - 不能!
- Can you whisper?  - Not really!
来吧
Come on.
昨晚...
Well, thanks for a...
多谢了
You know... an evening.
太可怕了
It was awful.
是啊 我想装一下来着 不过...
Yeah. I was going to pretend, but...
真的太可怕了
it was, truly.
那个叫泰瑞莎的女人...
That woman, Tessa...
怎么了?
What?
和鬼魂约会 是这几个月以来最有意思的案子了
Dated a ghost, most interesting case for months.
真是浪费了大好的机会!
What a wasted opportunity!
好吧
OK.
你感觉如何?
How are you feeling?
嗯
Hmm.
简直和以前一样 你坐在那里
It's just like old times, having you back here.
我感觉是最后一次给你做你最喜欢吃的东西
I thought I'd make your favourite, one last time.
哦 别说的跟生离死别似的
Oh. Don't sound so final about it,
- 我还会回来看你的  - 哦 你以前也那么说
- I will be visiting, you know.  - Ooh, I've heard that one before!
不 这次不一样了 不是吗?
No, it's different now, though, isn't it?
我们以为他去世了的时候和现在不一样
It's different to when we thought we'd lost him.
婚姻会改变一切的 约翰
Well, marriage changes everything, John.
- 是吗?  - 是啊 你可能想不到 但这是真的
- Does it?  - Yeah. You might not think it, but it does.
这是你人生中一段新的生活
It's a different phase in your life.
你会遇到新的朋友
You meet knew people,
因为你结婚了
becauses you're a couple,
以前的友谊就会消失
and then you just let your old friends slip away.
- 不会这样的  - 如果你找到了对的人
- It won't be like that.  - Well, if you've found the right one,
那个和你心灵相通的人 那就是世界上最棒的事
the person that you click with, it's the best thing in the world.
- 我找到了 我确定那就是她  - 我知道
- Well, I have. I know I have.  - Oh, I'm sure.
她很可爱
She's lovely.
是啊 我也这么觉得 那你呢?
Yeah, I think so. What about you?
我?
Me?
当你嫁给哈德森先生的时候 你是觉得你找到了对的人吗?
Did you think you'd found the right one when you married Mr Hudson?
不 那就像是一阵旋风
No. It was just a whirlwind thing for us.
- 我知道这事不一定靠谱 但我就跟着感觉走了  - 是啊
- I knew it wouldn't work, but I just got sort of swept along.  - Right.
后来我们去了弗罗里达
And then we moved to Florida.
我们共度了美好的时光
We had a fantastic time,
但是我不太知道他是做什么的 毒品
but of course I didn't know what he was up to. The drugs.
- 毒品?!  - 他经营着一个 呃...
- Drugs?!  - He was running, erm...
你们管它叫什么来着?
Oh, what do you call it?
呃... 一个...
Erm... A...
卡特尔
cartel.
还和一群坏人混在一起
And got in with a really bad crowd.
- 这样啊  - 我还发现他有别的女人
- Right.  - And then I found out about all the other women.
我不知道该怎么办
I didn't have a clue.
所以当他真的因为杀人被抓起来的时候
So, when he was actually arrested for blowing someone's head off,
说真的 我还真是松了口气
it was quite a relief, to be honest.
哦
Oh.
我和弗兰克之间是纯粹的肉体结合
It was purely physical between me and Frank.
我们根本离不开对方
We couldn't keep our hands off each other.
我知道 有一个晚上...
I know, there was one night...
哦 是夏洛克回来了吗?
Oh, is that Sherlock?
是吗?
Is it?
就是夏洛克
That's Sherlock.
呃
Urgh...
(他毁了所有人  而且还为此得到了勋章)
(没有答案的问题:为什么我的孩子会死去?)
一定还有别人
There are going to be others.
- 别人?  - 受害者 女人
- Others?  - Victims, women.
大多数鬼魂喜欢在一个地方作祟
Most ghosts tend to haunt a single house.
这个却到处乱转 你看
This ghost, however, is willing to commute. Look.
嗯...
Hmm...
不是你 不是你
Not you. Not you.
不是你 也不是你 不是你 不是你
Not you. Not you. Not you. Not you.
不是你 不是你
Not you. Not you.
也不是你
Not you.
不是你 不是你
Not you. Not you.
嗯...
Hmm...
也不是你
Not you.
不是你 不是你 不是你 也不是你 不是你 不是你
Not you. Not you. Not you. Not you. Not you. Not you.
不是你 不是你 不是你 不是你 不是你
Not you. Not you. Not you. Not you. Not you.
不是你 不是你 你 你 也不是你
Not you, you, you, or you, or you.
也不是你 不是你 不是你 不是你 不是你 不是你
Or not you, not you, not you, not you, not you, not you.
不是你
Not you.
嗨
Hi.
我是盖尔
Gail.
夏洛特
Charlotte.
罗宾
Robyn.
维奇
Vicky.
你们是怎么认识的?
How did you meet?
- 在酒吧里  - 他和我去同一个健身馆
- Came up to me in a pub.  - Same gym as me.
我们在公交车上闲聊起来的
We just got chatting on the bus.
网上认识的
Online.
- 叫什么?  - 我刚告诉你了
- Name?  - Told you.
- 他的名字  - 奥斯卡
- His name.  - Oscar.
- 迈克  - 特里
- Mike.  - Terry.
呃... 可爱的猴子
Erm... Love Monkey.
你们在哪约会?
Your place?
他家
His place.
地址?
Address?
什么都没发生
Nothing happened.
就是... 特别浪漫
It was just... very romantic.
四个晚上勾搭了四个女人 他一定有什么特别之处
Four women in four nights. He must have something special.
- 他很迷人  - 他善于倾听
- He was very charming.  - He listened.
他超可爱
He was sweet.
他有可爱的...
He had a lovely...
你没事吧?
You OK?
你的饭凉了 哈德森太太又要抱怨了
You've let your food go cold. Mrs. Hudson will play hell.
别打扰我 约翰
Not now, John.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
他有个可爱的动作
He had a lovely manner.
不同的名字 不同的地址
Different names, different addresses.
说说他是什么样子
Describe him.
金色短发
Short blonde hair.
深色长发
Dark hair. Long.
姜黄色 我喜欢姜
Ginger. I like gingers.
说不上来
Couldn't tell.
他戴着面具
He had a mask on.
他在"借尸还魂"
He's stealing the identity of corpses,
从讣告栏上获得他们的名字
getting their names from the obituary columns.
所有这些人
All single men.
他想到这些死人的公寓会空一阵子
He's using the dead man's flat
所以就物尽其用了
under the assumption it will be empty for a while.
免费的爱巢
Free love nest.
我想吐
I feel sick.
太阴森了
It's gruesome.
- 可怕  - 聪明...
- That's awful.  - Clever...
混蛋!
Bastard!
(混蛋!)
你好 泰瑞莎
Hello, Tessa.
回到正题
Meanwhile, back to business.
没人想住死人家里
No one wants to use a dead man's home.
住也起码要在它清理干净之后
At least not until it's been cleared.
所以他偷天换日
So, he disguises himself.
借用那个死人的住所和他的身份
Steals the man's home, steals his identity.
但只借用一晚 然后就消失
But only for one night. Then he's gone.
他不是鬼魂 约翰 他是只蜉蝣
He's not a ghost, John. He's a Mayfly.
他的生命只有一天
He lives for a day.
所以他想要什么?
So, what was it he was looking for?
工作?
Job?
- 园丁  - 厨师
- Gardener.  - Cook.
- 私人护理  - 我负责安全工作
- Private nurse.  - I do security work.
女佣
Maid.
很明显 你们都为同一个人工作
Obvious. You all work for the same person.
不 不 不是同一个雇主 该死!
No, no, not the same employer. Damn!
快点 我们可以的
Come on, we can do this.
完美的约会之夜?
Ideal night out?
射击粘土鸽子
Clay-pigeon shooting.
队列舞
Line dancing.
摄影
Pictures.
一边看电视一边喝葡萄酒
Wine in front of the telly.
地牢
Dungeon.
- 化妆品?  - 娇韵诗
- Make-up?  - Clarins.
香奈儿七号
No 7.
- 美宝莲  - 基本不用
- Maybelline.  - Nothing special.
都是便宜货
Whatever's cheap.
香水?
Perfume?
- 香奈儿  - 香奈儿
- Chanel.  - Chanel.
香奈儿
Chanel.
- 香奈儿  - 雅诗兰黛
- Chanel.  - Estee Lauder.
理想伴侣?
Ideal man?
乔治·克鲁尼
George Clooney.
- 噢...!  - 顾家型
- Oh...!  - Home-loving.
他要喜欢拥抱
He'd have to like cuddling.
- 细腻敏感  - 十条
- Caring.  - Ten things.
一... 他并不与众不同
One... someone who isn't competitive with other men.
二... 他不会一直
Two... someone who isn't constantly
试图通过男子气概证明自己...
trying to define himself by his masculinity...
有一个共同点
There's a unifying factor,
一定有
there has to be.
你们谁都没说有东西被偷了
None of you reported anything stolen.
保安 园丁 厨师 女佣 私人护理
Security guard, gardener, cook, maid, private nurse.
他虚构的身份是按照等级排序的
He's romancing his way up a pecking order.
某个人自己心中的等级 快点 好好想 除非...
Somebody's pecking order. Come on, think. Unless...
你有没有一个不能对任何人说起的秘密?
Do you have a secret you've never told anyone?
没有
No.
- 明白了!  - 你什么意思?
- Gotcha!  - What do you mean?
每个人都有秘密 而且都会马上否定
Everyone has secrets and they all replied too quickly.
- 走了  - 回见
- Got to go.  - See you.
- 不... 等等!  - 拜拜
- No... Wait!  - Bye-bye.
等等!
Wait!
不好意思 帅哥 有些秘密只能是秘密
Sorry, sexy, some secrets have to stay secret.
享受婚礼吧
Enjoy the wedding.
为什么? 为什么他和这么多女人约会 但不回她们的电话?
Why? Why would he date all of those women and not return their calls?
- 你漏了最显而易见的一点 兄弟  - 有吗?
- You're missing the obvious, mate.  - Am I?
他是个男人
He's a man.
但他为什么要假借他人身份?
But why would he change his identity?
也许他已经结婚了
Maybe he's married.
噢...
Oh...
已婚
Married.
真的太明显了
Obvious, really.
我们的蜉蝣男在试图逃脱
Our Mayfly Man was trying to escape
让人窒息的家庭生活的围城
the suffocating chains of domesticity
他不想每天晚上都靠电视打发时间
and instead of endless nights in watching the telly
也不想和那些他无法忍受的糟糕 可怕 无聊的人聚餐
or going to barbecues with the awful, dreadful, boring people he couldn't stand,
他利用聪明头脑和伪装能力脚踏多条船 他是...
he used his wits, cleverness and powers of disguise to play the field. He was...
经我再三考虑
On second thoughts,
我也许应该告诉你这个显而易见的一点
I probably should have told you about the elephant in the room.
但是 它更进一步的让我明白
However, it does help to further illustrate
约翰对我来说有多重要
how invaluable John is to me.
在人情世故上 华生的才能和我办案能力不相上下
I can read a crime scene the way he can understand a human being.
我过去常想这就是我与众不同的地方 我现在也是这么想的
I used to think that's what made me special, quite frankly I still do.
但是一点忠告
But a word to the wise,
如果你们有需要我们帮助的
should any of you require the services of either of us,
我可以解决谋杀案
I will solve your murder,
但只有约翰·华生可以拯救你的人生
but it takes John Watson to save your life.
相信我 我本该知道
Trust me on that, I should know,
他屡次三番通过各种方式救了我
he's saved mine so many times and in so many ways.
这是一个关于两个男人的故事
This blog is the story of two men
也是一场关于谋杀 悬案和故意伤害的
and their, frankly, ridiculous adventures
荒诞冒险
of murder, mystery and mayhem.
但今天开启了新的篇章
But from now on, there's a new story.
一场更大的冒险
A bigger adventure.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请起立 斟满美酒 并举杯
pray, charge your glasses and be upstanding.
今天 玛丽·伊丽莎白·华生
Today begin the adventures
和约翰·哈米什·华生
of Mary Elizabeth Watson
将开始他们新的冒险
and John Hamish Watson.
我们在此聚首有两个原因...
The two reasons why every single one of us is...
你说什么?
What did you say?
你说...
You said...
"约翰·哈米什·华生"
"John Hamish Watson."
你说的 你说"哈米什"
You said that. You said "Hamish."
这位是著名侦探 夏洛克·福尔摩斯
This is a famous detective, it's Sherlock Holmes
以及他的助手约翰·哈米什·华生
and his partner, John Hamish Watson.
你怎么知道的?
How did you know?
你怎么会知道他的中名的?
How did you know his middle name?
他很讨厌这名字 从不告诉别人
He never tells anyone, he hates it.
约翰·H·华生?
John "H" Watson?
没错
Yep.
- 亨利?  - 别乱叫
- Henry?  - Shut up.
汉弗莱?
Humphrey?
够了
Shut up.
希金斯呢?
Higgins?
一边去!
Go away!
很久之后他才告诉我
It took him years to confide in me.
累啊...
Oh...
这是我的出生证明
That's my birth certificate.
是的
Yep.
而那个女人... 她也知道
And the woman... she knew.
是哈米什
Hamish.
约翰·哈米什·华生
John Hamish Watson,
如果你们要给小孩取名的话
just if you were looking for baby names.
鬼知道她在哪
God knows where she is.
滚出我的大脑 我很忙!
Out of my head, I am busy!
这个名字只被公开过一次
There's only one time that name's been made public.
一定要写在邀请函上吗?
Does it have to be on the invitation?
这是你的名字
It's your name.
- 是传统...  - 太好笑了...
- It's traditional...  - It's funny...
享受婚礼吧...
Enjoy the wedding...
享受婚礼吧
Enjoy the wedding.
婚礼 你知道婚礼的事
The wedding. You knew about the wedding.
更重要的是 说明你看过婚礼请柬了
More importantly, you'd seen a wedding invitation.
看过请柬的人绝不到一百个
Now barely 100 people had seen that invitation.
而蜉蝣男只见过五个女人
The Mayfly Man only saw five women.
一个人两种情况都符合...
For one person to be in both groups...
可能是巧合
could be a coincidence.
夏洛克!
Oh, Sherlock!
关于巧合是怎么说来着?
What do we say about coincidences?
宇宙不会这么懒
The universe is rarely so lazy.
- 所以 最有可能的是?  - 有人不遗余力地
- So, the balance of probability is?  - Someone went to great lengths
想在婚礼上找到什么
to find out something about this wedding.
- 怎样不遗余力?  - 他们撒谎了 谎报身份
- What great lengths?  - They lied. Assumed false identities.
- 也就是说?  - 有犯罪动机
- Which suggests?  - Criminal intent.
也意味着?
Also suggests?
有情报 有预谋
Intelligence, planning.
显然 但更重要的是?
Clearly. But more importantly?
蜉蝣男
The Mayfly Man.
蜉蝣男...
The Mayfly Man is...
今日在场!
Here today!
抱歉 我...
Ooh, sorry. I...
再来一杯吗 先生?
Another glass, sir?
谢谢 当然 谢谢
Thank you, yes, thank you. Yes.
有事要发生 就在这里
Something's going to happen, right here.
刚才说到哪了?
Now, where were we?
随时可能
Could be any second.
你控制了整个房间的人
You have control of the room.
想起来了
Ah, yes.
举杯起立 非常好 谢谢
Raising glasses and standing up. Very good. Thank you.
别搞砸了
Don't lose it.
请再次落座
And down again.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
俗话说好演讲要简短
people tell you not to milk a good speech.
早点打住 留下欢笑
Get off early, leave 'em laughing.
我会谨记的明智建议
Wise advice I'll certainly try to bear in mind.
但现在...
But for now...
第二场开始!
part two!
第二场动作戏加多
Part two is more action-based.
我会四处走动 调整一下状态
I'm going to walk around, shake things up a bit.
谁会参加婚礼呢? 这是关键问题
Who'd go to a wedding? That's the question.
谁会大费周章地
Who would bother to go to any lengths
混进婚礼呢?
to get themselves to a wedding?
是个人都会
Well, everyone.
婚礼多棒啊 大爱婚礼
Weddings are great, love a wedding.
- 他在干嘛?  - 出事了
- What's he doing?  - Something's wrong.
也大爱约翰
And John's great too.
永远说不够 皮毛都没夸完
Haven't said that enough, barely scratched the surface.
我可以聊一整晚
I could go on all night
他的深度和复杂性
about the depth and complexity of his jumpers,
而且他会做饭
and he can cook.
做... 某种东西 有豆子...
Does... erm... a thing. A thing with peas...
只做了一次 或许没有豆子 或许不是他做的
Once. Might not be peas, might not be him.
但他唱歌也很好听 有可能记错人了
But he's got a great singing voice, or somebody does.
太多了 太多了 太多了 太多了!
Too many, too many, too many, too many!
抱歉 约翰的玩笑说多了
Sorry, too many jokes about John.
- 现在...  - 犯罪意图
- Now...  - Criminal intent.
说到哪了? 对
Where was I? Ah, yes.
极其大费周章
Extraordinary lengths.
演讲 演讲
Speech. Speech.
我们来谈谈...
Let's talk about...
所有的一切都预示着...
All of which is suggestive of...
谋杀! 抱歉 我说谋杀了吗?
Murder! Sorry, did I say murder?
我想说婚姻来着
I meant to say marriage.
但你们理解 如果你仔细想想的话
But, you know, they're quite similar procedures,
它们的程序极为相似
when you think about it.
参加者们都互相认识
The participants tend to know each other
因一方去世而结束
and it's over when one of them's dead.
平心而论 谋杀更快捷 珍宁 这个人怎么样?
In fairness, murder is a lot quicker though. Janine, what about this one?
相貌还行? 关键是 他的女朋友穿着不舒服的新内衣
Acceptably hot? More importantly, his girlfriend's wearing new uncomfortable underwear
都懒得捡他外套上的线头 或者指出他脖子上的油污
and hasn't bothered to pick this thread off his jacket, or point out the grease smudge on his neck.
他会独自回家 还是个漫画和科幻小说迷
He's going home alone. Also he's a comics and sci-fi geek,
这种人都很有感激心 值得你花时间
they're always tremendously grateful, really put the hours in.
杰夫 去男厕
Jeff, the gents.
马上去洗手间 拜托
Loos now, please.
- 叫我格雷格  - 洗手间
- Greg.  - The loos, please.
- 为什么?  - 我怎么知道 或许轮到你了
- Why?  - Oh, I don't know, maybe it's your turn.
(封锁这个地方)
说到这个 我还真想去了
Yeah, actually, now you mention it.
夏洛克 这演讲... 什么时候结束?
Sherlock, any chance of a... an end date for this speech?
该切蛋糕了
Got to cut the cake.
女士们 先生们
Oh, ladies and gentlemen,
他就受不了我终于有机会当众演讲了
can't stand it when I finally get the chance to speak for once.
梵蒂冈的配角
Vatican cameos.
他说什么? 这什么意思?
What did he say? What does that mean?
战斗状态 有人要死了
Battle stations, someone's going to die.
什么?!
What?!
缩小范围 缩小范围
Narrow it down. Narrow it down.
缩小范围!
Narrow it down!
不 不!
No, no!
不是你!
Not you!
是你 一直是你
You. It's always you.
约翰·华生 你保证我不走弯路
John Watson, you keep me right.
我该怎么做?
What do I do?
你已经做了
You've already done it.
不要想着破案
Don't solve the murder.
想着救人
Save the life.
抱歉 有点跑题了
Sorry, off piste a bit.
回到正题 咻!
Back now. Phew!
我们玩个游戏吧 叫"杀人游戏"
Let's play a game. Let's play murder.
夏洛克!
Sherlock!
想象有人会在婚礼上被谋杀
Imagine someone's going to get murdered at a wedding.
你们会选谁?
Who exactly would you pick?
你肯定是热门人选 亲爱的
I think you're a popular choice at the moment, dear.
如果有人把哈德森太太的眼镜放到她够不到的地方
If someone could move Mrs Hudson's glass just slightly out of reach,
那将感激不尽
that would be lovely.
更重要的是 谁只能在婚礼上被杀?
More importantly, who could you only kill at a wedding?
大多数人在任何一个地方杀死都行
Most people you can kill any old place.
作为思想训练
As a mental exercise,
我经常策划谋杀朋友和同事
I've often planned the murder of friends and colleagues.
现在 我要毒死约翰
Now, John, I'd poison.
吃货很容易死 我会给他吃化学药剂
Sloppy eater, dead easy. I've given him chemicals and compounds,
这样他根本注意不到
that way he's never even noticed.
他有次昏睡了整个周三 毫无头绪
He missed a whole Wednesday once, didn't have a clue.
谋杀雷斯垂德太容易了 至今没人试过真是奇迹
Lestrade's so easy to kill it's a miracle no-one's succumbed to the temptation.
我有哥哥家的钥匙 心血来潮的时候可以闯入掐死他
I've got keys to my brother's house, I could break in and asphyxiate him, if the whim arose.
他生气了 对吧?
He's pissed, isn't he?
再说一遍
So, once again,
谁是你只能在这杀死的?
who could you only kill here?
显然这是难得的机会
Clearly it's a rare opportunity,
所以是一个不经常露面的人
so it's someone who doesn't get out much.
尤其是他提前好几个月
Someone for whom a planned social encounter
知道有社交活动
known about months in advance is an exception.
对他有特殊意义的机会
Has to be a unique opportunity.
由于在公众场合杀人非常困难
And since killing someone in public is difficult,
而又不能私下里动手
killing them in private isn't an option.
那这个人应该住在无法接近或者不知名的地方
Someone who lives in an inaccessible or unknown location, then.
或许是个隐士
Someone private perhaps,
极度关注个人安全
obsessed with personal security.
或许还受过威胁
Possibly someone under threat.
- 詹姆斯·肖尔托少校 他是谁?  - 我觉得他不会来
- Major James Sholto, who he?  - I don't think he's coming.
他会来的
He'll be there.
这些年你住在哪?
Where are you living these days?
很偏僻的小地方
Oh, way out in the middle of nowhere.
来自死者家庭和媒体的压力不断
The press and families gave him hell.
他收到的死亡威胁比你还多
He gets more death threats than you.
一个隐士?
A recluse?
小型王室的职员
Small household staff.
- 工作?  - 园丁 厨师 私人护士 女佣
- Job?  - Gardener. Cook. Private nurse. Maid.
额外的安保薪酬很高
High turnover for additional security.
- 我负责安保工作  - 或许都签了保密协议
- I do security work.  - Probably all signed confidentiality agreements.
- 你们有不可告人的秘密吗?  - 没有
- Do you have a secret you've never told anyone? - No.
但仍然有个问题 大问题
There is another question that remains. Rather a big one,
非常大... 会怎么做? 怎么当众杀人呢?
a huge one... how would you do it? How do you kill someone in public?
一定有办法 都计划好的
There has to be a way. This has been planned.
- 福尔摩斯先生!  - 你好 阿奇 你怎么想的?
- Mr Holmes!  - Hello, Archie, what's your theory?
回答正确就把无头修女给你
Get this right and there's a headless nun in it for you.
- 隐形人可以做到  - 人物 情节 起因 时间 地点?
- The invisible man could do it.  - The who, what, why, when, where?
隐形人拿着隐形的刀 就是想杀死卫兵的那个人
The invisible man with the invisible knife. The one who tried to kill the Guardsman.
(地点)
(计划)
(彩排)
本布瑞吉?
Bainbridge?
本布瑞吉!
Bainbridge!
哦 不只是有计划... 还彩排过了
Oh, not just planned... planned and rehearsed.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
现在有个小插曲
there will now be a short interlude.
敬新娘和新郎...
The bride and groom...
敬新娘和新郎
The bride and groom.
肖尔托少校将被杀害 我不知道是谁 会怎么下手 但这事情肯定会发生
Major Sholto's going to be murdered, I don't know how or by whom, but it's going to happen.
抱歉 让路 私下商议
Excuse me, coming through. Consulting.
- 待在这  - 一定要小心
- Stay here.  - Please be careful.
抱歉 让下路
Excuse me. Coming through.
抱歉
Excuse me.
不好意思 又来一个 抱歉
I'm sorry, one more. Oops. I'm so sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么会记不得哪个房间? 你过目不忘啊
How can you not remember which room? You remember everything.
- 我得清理内存!  - 是207
- I have to delete something!  - 207.
肖尔托少校? 肖尔托少校!
Major Sholto? Major Sholto!
- 肖尔托少校!  - 如果有人想取我的性命
- Major Sholto!  - If someone's about to make an attempt on my life,
这也不是第一次了 我准备好了
it won't be the first time. I'm ready.
- 少校 让我们进去  - 把门踹开
- Major, let us in.  - Kick the door down.
我不会开门的
I really wouldn't.
我手里有把枪 还有一辈子的不幸回忆
I have a gun in my hand and a lifetime of unfortunate reflexes.
你在里面不安全 不管是谁要杀你 锁上门是不够的
You're not safe in there. Whoever's after you, we know a locked room doesn't stop him.
拿着隐形刀的隐形人
The invisible man with the invisible knife.
- 我不知道他的手法 我阻止不了他 而这意味着他还会动手的!  - 那就破解它!
- I don't know how he does it. I can't stop him and that means he'll do it again!  - Solve it, then!
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
你是大名鼎鼎的福尔摩斯先生 开始破案吧
You're the famous Mr Holmes, solve the case, on you go.
告诉我他的手法 我会开门的
Tell me how he did it and I'll open the door.
拜托 现在没时间玩游戏
Please, this is no time for games,
让我们进去 你很危险!
just let us in, you're in danger!
你们在这里也很危险
So are you, so long as you're here.
求你们了 别管我
Please, leave me.
即使我有官衔 我也不希望拖累他人
Despite my reputation, I really don't approve of collateral damage.
- 那就破案  - 什么?
- Solve it.  - Sorry?
就像他说的 只要你破案 他就会开门
Solve it and he'll open the door, like he said.
- 以前我解不开 现在为什么就能解开?  - 因为现在需要解开
- I couldn't solve it before, how can I solve it now?  - Because it matters now.
你在说什么呢? 她在说什么呢? 好好管管你老婆
What are you talking about? What's your wife talking about? Get your wife under control!
她说得没错
She's right.
- 你怎么说变就变!  - 不 她是对的 别说了!
- Oh, you've changed!  - No, she is. Shut up!
你不是一个解密者 从来不是
You are not a puzzle-solver, you never have been.
你只会作秀!
You're a drama queen!
现在有人要死了 游戏开始... 赶紧破案!
Now, there's a man in there about to die, the game is on... solve it!
本布瑞吉?
Bainbridge?
本布瑞吉!
Bainbridge!
- 实话实说 他也很会作秀  - 我知道
- Though in fairness, he's a drama queen too.  - I know.
肖尔托少校 没人会来杀你的
Major Sholto, no one's coming to kill you.
几小时前你就已经死了
I'm afraid you've already been killed several hours ago.
你说什么呢?
What did you say?
不要解开腰带
Don't take off your belt.
腰带?
My belt?
没错 就是腰带
His belt, yes.
我们还没到 本布瑞吉就被杀了
Bainbridge was stabbed hours before we even saw him,
其实是被他的腰带刺杀的
but it was through his belt.
紧系在腰部的腰带
Tight belt, worn high on the waist.
很轻易就能将刀片刺入腹部
Very easy to push a small blade through the fabric
甚至都察觉不到
and you wouldn't even feel it.
腰带系着的时候察觉不到伤口
The belt would bind the flesh together when it was tied tight.
- 没错  - 但解开的时候...
- Exactly.  - But when you took it off...
伤口迸发 行刺成功
Delayed-action stabbing.
这样不在场证明就能轻易伪造 肖尔托少校?
All the time in the world to create an alibi. Major Sholto?
那...
So...
我被自己的军装杀死
I was to be killed by my uniform.
真是讽刺
How appropriate.
他破案了 少校
He solved the case, Major,
你要把门打开 我们说好的
you're supposed to open the door now. A deal is a deal.
我本来应该上交军装
I'm not even supposed to have this any more,
但他们特别照顾我 让我留着它
they gave me special dispensation to keep it.
我不知道脱掉军装我还能做什么
I couldn't imagine life out of this uniform.
但现在看起来 我可以不脱掉它们了
I suppose, given the circumstances, I don't have to.
既然那么多人希望我死
When so many want you dead,
磨磨蹭蹭又有什么用呢
it hardly seems good manners to argue.
不管你在做什么 詹姆斯 立刻停下来!
Whatever you're doing in there, James, stop it, right now!
我要破门而入了!
I will kick this door down!
福尔摩斯先生 我认为我们很像
Mr Holmes, you and I are similar, I think.
- 是的 我同意  - 当死则死 我说得对吧?
- Yes, I think we are.  - There's a proper time to die, isn't there?
当然如此
Of course there is.
当死亡来临的时候不应该逃避
And one should embrace it when it comes.
要像战士一样面对
Like a soldier.
话是没错 但不应该在约翰的婚礼上死!
Of course one should, but not at John's wedding!
你和我都不会那么做的
We wouldn't do that, would we,
是吧?
you and me?
我们不能这么对约翰·华生
We would never do that to John Watson.
我要踹门了
I'm going to break it down.
等一下 你不用那样做了
Wait, wait, wait, you won't have to.
看来我需要医疗救助
I believe I am in need of medical attention.
我就是医生
I believe I'm your doctor.
很好
Pretty good.
只是旋转的时候要注意
Just hold your nerve on your turning.
我们干嘛要彩排?
Why do we have to rehearse?
因为我们要在众人面前跳舞
Because we are about to dance together in public
而你舞技不行
and your skills are appalling.
- 你真是个好老师  - 嗯
- Wow, you're a good teacher.  - Hmm.
而且很会跳舞
And you're a brilliant dancer.
想不想知道我的秘密 珍宁?
Can I let you in on something, Janine?
你说吧
Go on, then.
我喜欢跳舞 一直都很喜欢
I love dancing, I've always loved it.
真的假的?
Seriously?
看着
Watch out.
哦!
Oh!
虽然目前对于办案没什么帮助
Never really comes up in crime work, but, you know,
- 但我希望有天能碰上一个这样的案子  - 哦 真希望你...
- I live in hope of the right case.  - Oh, I wish you weren't...
不是现在的你
whatever it is you are.
- 是的  - 真是太好了 夏洛克
- I know.  - Well, glad to see you've pulled, Sherlock,
你解开了我婚礼上的凶杀案
what with murderers running riot at my wedding.
一起谋杀案... 一起未遂的谋杀案
One murderer... one nearly murderer.
就喜欢夸张... 你应该试试和他住在一起
Loves to exaggerate... you should try living with him.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
我把他带来了
Got him for you.
照相师 很好 谢谢你
Ah, the photographer, excellent. Thank you.
我可以看一眼你的照相机吗?
May I have a look at your camera?
呃 怎么了? 我都快到家了
Erm, what's this about? I was halfway home.
你快点开车就已经到家了
You should have driven faster.
好 很好!
Ah, yes. Yes!
太好了
Very good.
看到了吗... 棒极了
Now you see... perfect.
怎么回事? 你能解释一下吗?
What is? Are you going to tell us?
你自己看吧
Try looking yourself.
- 看什么?  - 凶手在照片里吗?
- Look for what?  - Is the murderer in these photographs?
不在照片里
It's not what's in the photographs,
一张他的照片也没有
it's what's not in them. Not in any of them.
夏洛克?
Sherlock?
我们谈过了 别总显摆...
The showing-off thing, we've discussed it before...
婚礼上有个人永远都不会在照片里露脸
There is always a man at a wedding who is not in any photograph,
他想去哪里都行
who can go anywhere.
还可以带着一个工具包
And even carry an equipment bag around with him if he likes.
照片不会拍下他的长相
And you never even see his face.
大家只会看到...
You only ever see...
他照的照片
the camera.
你在干嘛? 怎么回事?
What are you doing? What is this?
乔纳森·斯莫尔 今天的临时婚礼摄影师
Jonathan Small, today's substitute wedding photographer,
就是我们说的蜉蝣男
known to us as the Mayfly Man.
他的弟弟就是在那次行动中牺牲的新兵之一
His brother was one of the raw recruits killed in that incursion.
乔纳森一直想找肖尔托复仇
Johnny sought revenge on Sholto,
他想法设法接近肖尔托
worked his way through Sholto's staff,
他发现了可乘之机
found what he needed.
婚礼请柬
An invitation to a wedding.
这次肖尔托一定会公开露面
The one time Sholto would have to be out in public.
他制定了计划 还进行了预演
So he made his plan and rehearsed the murder,
确保每个环节万无一失
making sure of every last detail.
精密而残酷
Brilliant, ruthless,
而且疯狂的偏执
and almost certainly a monomaniac.
但说实话 他的摄影技巧确实不错
Though, in fairness, his photographs are actually quite good.
你需要这个吧
Everything you need is on that.
或许应该逮捕他 随你便
You probably ought to arrest him or something.
你一直随身携带手铐吗?
Do you always carry handcuffs?
- 低调 妹子  - 快来
- Down, girl.  - Come on, quick.
应该被捕的人不是我 福尔摩斯先生
It's not me you should be arresting, Mr Holmes.
我不能逮捕别人 是别人来做
Oh, I don't do the arresting, I just farm that out.
肖尔托才是杀人犯 不是我
Sholto, he's the killer, not me.
我应该快刀斩乱麻
I should have killed him quicker.
不应该耍那些小聪明
I shouldn't have tried to be clever.
你应该快点开车回家
You should have driven faster.
好了
Right.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen, just one last thing
在舞会之前 我想先说几句
before the evening begins properly.
对于今天早些时候的小插曲 我深表抱歉
Apologies for earlier, a crisis arose and was dealt with.
但那些都不重要
More importantly, however,
因为今天一对新人在这里盟誓
today we saw two people make vows.
我从没有 今后也不会
I've never made a vow in my life
许下任何承诺
and after tonight I never will again.
所以今天在大家面前
So, here in front of you all,
我将许下今生唯一的承诺
my first and last vow.
玛丽和约翰
Mary and John,
无论今后
whatever it takes,
发生什么
whatever happens,
从此刻开始
from now on,
我都会守护你们
I swear I will always be there.
我发誓
Always.
我会守护着你们三个
For all three of you.
呃... 不好意思... 你们二个
Erm... sorry, I mean... I mean two of you.
你们二个 你们两个 不好意思 我数学不好
All two of you. Both of you, in fact. I just miscounted.
好了 该跳舞了
Anyway, it's time for dancing.
请接着演奏 谢谢
Play the music again, please. Thank you.
好了 大家尽情跳吧 不要拘束
OK, everybody, just dance, don't be shy.
都跳起来 很好
Dancing, please. Very good.
抱歉 我不应该多说了一个人的
Sorry, that was one more deduction than I was really expecting.
- 多说?  - 食欲大增...
- Deduction?  - Increased appetite...
- 我要饿死了  - 口味改变
- I'm starving.  - Change of taste perception.
我怎么会选这种酒 真是难喝得要命!
Oh, I chose this wine, but it's bloody awful!
早上你还恶心了
You were sick this morning.
你以为那只是婚礼前的紧张
You assumed it was just wedding nerves.
我跟你说的时候 你还冲我发火
You got angry with me when I mentioned it to you.
- 所有一切都表明了  - 表明什么?
- All the signs are there.  - The signs?
预示着有新生命
The signs of three.
什么?
What?
玛丽 你应该去验一下孕
Mary, I think you should do a pregnancy test.
怀孕初期的检验结果应该是...
Well, the statistics for the first trimester are...
别说了!
Shut up!
快闭嘴
Just shut up.
抱歉
Sorry.
为什么他比我先看出来?
How did he notice before me?
- 我可是医生  - 今天你休息
- I'm a bloody doctor.  - It's your day off.
你才应该去休息!
It's your day off!
不要紧张
Stop. Stop panicking.
- 我不紧张  - 怀孕的是我 我很紧张!
- I'm not panicking.  - I'm pregnant, I'm panicking!
不要紧张
Don't panic.
你们都不要紧张
None of you panic.
完全没必要紧张
Absolutely no reason to panic.
- 就像你懂似的!  - 我当然懂 你们肯定是最棒的父母
- Oh, and you'd know, of course!  - Yes, I would. You're already the best parents in the world,
- 你们准备得这么充分  - 准备什么了?
- look at all the practice you've had.  - What practice?
你们已经成功地把我养到这么大了
Well, you're hardly going to need me around now that you've got a real baby on the way.
- 你还好吧?  - 很好!
- Are you all right?  - Yeah!
- 你们俩去跳舞吧  - 嗯?
- Dance. Both of you now, go, dance.  - Hmm?
- 我们站在这里 大家都会好奇我们在说什么  - 嗯
- We can't just stand here, people will wonder what we're talking about.  - Right.
那你怎么办?
Well, what about you?
- 我们三个人不能一起跳舞  - 是的 咳咳
- Yeah, we can't all three dance, there are limits.  - Yes, there are. Ahem.
来吧 老公 我们跳舞去
Come on, husband, let's go.
- 这不是华尔兹吧?  - 不是
- This isn't a Waltz, is it?  - No.
别担心 我教过他
Don't worry, I have been tutoring him.
没错 在贝克街 我们拉上窗帘在屋里跳舞 有一次哈德森太太看见了
He did, you know. Baker Street, behind closed curtains. Mrs Hudson came in one time.
然后绯闻就传开了!
I don't know how those rumours started!
∮ 我转过头去 不由自主 ∮
∮ Spinnin' my head around and taking my body under ∮
∮ 哦 多么美好的夜晚 ∮
∮ Oh, what a night ∮
∮ 哦 我已经 ∮
∮ Oh, I ∮
∮ 感受到了那种冲动 ∮
∮ I got a funny feelin' when she walked ∮
∮ 在她进来的时候 ∮
∮ In the room ∮
∮ 嘿 但是 ∮
∮ Hey, I ∮
∮ 那种感觉稍纵即逝 ∮
∮ As I recall it ended much too soon ∮
∮ 哦 多么美好的夜晚 ∮
∮ Oh, what a night ∮
∮ 为什么我这么晚才明白 ∮
∮ Why'd it take so long to see the light ∮
∮ 看似模糊 其实我明白 ∮
∮ Seemed so wrong but now it seems so right ∮
∮ 多么美丽的姑娘 多么美好的夜晚 ∮
∮ What a lady, what a night ∮
∮ 哦 我被电到了 就像被闪电击中一样 ∮
∮ Oh, I felt a rush like a rolling ball of thunder ∮
∮ 我转过头去 不由自主 ∮
∮ Spinnin' my head around and taking my body under ∮
∮ 哦 多么美好的夜晚 ∮
∮ Oh, what a night ∮